# DAVID S. JACKSON

WEB DEVELOPER

dsj@dsj.net 🔀

678.779.9060



github.com/deepbsd (



deepbsd-portfolio.herokuapp.com

# STATEMENT

I graduated from the Thinkful Web Development Program. I've studied the MERN stack with a focus on React on the front end and Mongo and Node on the back end. I've used Linux as my daily driver for about 22 years, so I'm very comfortable on the BASH command line. Additionally, I'm comfortable programming in Node.js and also in Python. I've also been helping new students as a Teaching Assistant for Thinkful. I'm enthusiastic about React/Redux and reusable components as well as dynamic state management. I'm eager to join a positive culture where I can grow and mature as a developer, where I can contribute my skills, experience and excitement.

# **EXPERIENCE**

# **Teaching Assistant**

Thinkful May 2017 - Present

Help students solve code assignments in introductory JS classes. Primarily creating simple JS apps using CSS and jQuery. Also helped with Intro to Python classes for the Data Science Program using Jupyter Notebooks and the Pandas and SciKit libraries.

#### **Software Development**

Self-Employed

March 1996 - Present

Run a home network consisting of 30 PCs and notebook computers, running services ranging from SSH to HTTP to Samba and NFS. I have personally built or rebuilt each of these computers. I write automation scripts that set up user accounts and environments and build local web apps.

#### Co-Author

MacMillan Publishing - Special Edition: Using SGML

August 1995 - March 1996

Wrote about 60% of the content of this 600+ page book, explaining various aspects of SGML, including the history and applications, including HTML. The XML spec was released not longer after the publishing date of this volume.

## **Technical Writer**

Solar Turbines – Engineering Parts Lister/Technical

August 1991 – March 1996

Created illustrated parts manuals for large, custom turbo machinery and ensured repair manuals and parts lists reflected the final, as-shipped configurations of delivered customer packages.

#### **Technical Writer**

General Dynamics – Engineering Parts Lister/Technical Documentation

August 1985 – July 1991

Wrote documentation for Army and Navy Cruise Missile projects GLCM/SLCM. Prepared engineering parts lists according to MIL-STD specs. Worked with engineers and designers to produce exploded subsystem views for government customers.

## **PROJECTS**

**CodeDrills** 

codedrills.netlify.com

A project to help Web Devs prepare for technical interviews. I built both back and front ends. Uses React/Redux, Node, Mongo, and more. Back end hosted on Heroku, front-end hosted on Netlify.

#### GunBase

firearmbase.herokuapp.com

A project to maintain a firearms inventory for insurance and legal purposes. Front-end uses jQuery and back-end uses Mongo, Node, Mongoose, Jest. Both front and back ends are hosted on Heroku.

#### **SwapiQuiz**

swapiquiz.herokuapp.com

This was my Star Wars Characters Quiz. It was my first project that consumed a public API. It used jQuery and HTML/CSS3 and accessed the Star Wars API using AJAX/JSON over HTTP.

# **SKILLS**

#### Languages

Javascript/Node, Python3, Bash, HTML/CSS3, MongoDB/Shell, Some PHP/Wordpress, Some Ruby/Rails

#### Frameworks/Libraries

React/Redux, jQuery, Mocha/Chai, Enzyme/Jest, Express, Mongoose, Ajax, Gulp, Npm, Jasmine, Immutable.js

#### Tools

Git/Github, Vim, Sass, JSON, XML, Atom, Sublime Text, nvm, i3 Tilling WM, Slack, Postman

#### **Platforms**

Linux, MacOS, FreeBSD, Virtualbox/ Vagrant (Windows not preferred), Heroku, Netlify, TravisCI

# **EDUCATION**

## Thinkful

March 2017 - December 2018
Created three full-stack applications and a portfolio site. It was a self-paced course where I built the app assignments with a great deal of freedom and could get help from my 1-on-1 mentor, from online conferences, and from the Thinkful Slack community.

#### Skillcrush

July 2015 – February 2017

I took several "blueprints," each of which consisted of several courses.

I took blueprints in Web Design,
Beginning Javascript, Ruby and Rails,
and also Wordpress Development.

#### Oreilly School of Technology

December 2014 – July 2015
I earned an Advanced Python
Programming certificate, having
completed four courses from
beginning programming concepts
through many advanced concepts,
using decorators, generators, and
many data structures, including
building a virtual disk in memory and
a simple multi-threaded application
using process workers.

# **Brigham Young University**

1985

Bachelor's Degree in English

## HOBBIES

Motorcycling, bicycling, & building computers